Dear Asos,

Please find attached a copy of my CV for your consideration.

My name is Ray Berry, I am an experienced Scrum Master with many years of managing projects with both onshore and offshore located teams. I have in-depth knowledge and application of Scrum Agile processes including: sprint planning; daily stand-ups; two week sprint cycles; sprint reviews and retrospectives. I have Scrum PSM1 certification and good understanding of Jira for issue/user story management.

I really enjoy the development and technical side of business and embrace modern technology. I cross-trained into developing mobile Apps. I have learnt Swift, which is a C-based language. This really provided me with insights into the dynamics and requirements of a development team. I am a great team player and my previous role encompassed all the required qualities listed :scrum master; team leading; stakeholder management. As well as the Scrum and project management experience, I now have good technical understanding of the mobile app development process having published Apps of my own on the Apple App Store.

I feel that I have the necessary skills of the Agile Delivery Manager you are seeking I look forward to hearing from you.



# Ray Berry

## **SUMMARY - Agile Delivery Manager**

I am an experienced and qualified Scrum Master (PSM1) with a background in financial, retail and automotive industries delivering IT projects with both offshore and onshore teams. As well as ERP integration, I have a good understanding of the mobile App development process with technical knowledge in developing and deploying Apple Apps.



07951 010595



# App Portfolio



Bourne, Nr Peterborough

in linkedin.com/in/rav-berry

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Agile Qualified Scrum Master PSM1 Project Management Jira Confluence Sprint planning
- UI/UX Design
  Wireframes
  Mock-ups
  Human Interface Guidelines
- iOS Developer Swift 5 Xcode 10 Github Firebase CoreData Realm CoreML ARKit
- Rest API JSON Cocoapods Carthage Alamofire MVC Tableviews Collection Views SpriteKit
- VideoStreaming(HLS)
  User Authentication (FaceID, TouchID)
- TDD XCTest
- ERP process integration
  B2B
  EDI
  XML
  AS2

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### iOS Developer

Freelance

10/2017 - Present

Bourne, UK

- Good knowledge of Swift 5 and Xcode 10.
- Developed the following Apps:
  - FileIT Inventory Management to track inventory to assist with home insurance or moving house. Uses Core Data, User Authentication and Core Graphics Animation.
  - Weather using Rest APIs, JSON and GPS location data to retrieve weather data.
  - Augmented Reality Tape measure using ARkit and Scenekit to measure 3D objects.
  - Video Streaming using HLS (Http Live Streaming) to showcase apps that I have developed.
- UI/UX Design experience of creating wireframes and mock-ups.
- TDD Use of XCtest and XCUITest.

#### **Development Manager(Scrum Master)** BGL Group Ltd

2012 - 10/2017

Peterborough UK

- Scrum Master for the 'WatchMen' team. Knowledge and use of Scrum Agile processes including: sprint planning; daily stand-ups; two week sprint cycles; sprint reviews and retrospectives.
- Successfully managed a scrum team delivering internal financial services projects.
- Qualified Professional Scrum Master with PSM1 certification.
- Use of Scrum Poker, Three Amigos, Scrum of Scrums and burn down charts.
- Understanding and use of Kanban boards.
- Use of pair programming within the team.
- Understanding and using the Atlassian tools: Jira and Confluence to manage sprints, user stories and updating the sprint and product backlog. Understanding and use of JOL (Jira guery language).
- Use of Slack and Trello.

#### **NEU IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2010 - 2012

Hull, UK

- Managing a cross-section of IT projects ranging from senior management reporting, cost reduction exercises, automation of business interfaces between JDE and Siebel; Manugistics and EDI packages.
- The project management encompassed resource allocation, budget control, prioritisation, risk analysis, project delivery and post implementation reviews.

#### **European IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2006 - 2009

Hull, UK

Project managing teams as well as working with external off-shore support from Bangalore, India to ensure implementation of a demand planning tool (Manugistics 7.2) across sixteen countries in Europe. Managing project budget for Europe for over £1m for Manugistics rollouts.

#### **EDI Senior Business Analyst**

Reckitt Benckiser

2003 - 2006

Hull, UK

- I was responsible for EDI within Europe for RB. I was responsible for a team of five supporting the EDI infrastructure within seventeen countries across Europe.
- Consultancy role on EDI interface design and development into JD Edwards.
- Good EDI mapping experience using Inovis TLI series visual mapper. Mapping in TRADACOM, EDIFACT, ANSI X12 and EANCOM subsets i.e HANCOM. Written code in RPG for interface routines.

#### **Freelance EDI Consultant**

Freelance

1998 - 2003

Chiswick/Slough, UK

EDI integration specialist in BPCS and JD Edwards using Harbinger /Inovis Trusted Link I series EDI interfacing products and RPG.

### **EDUCATION**

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Cambridge College of Arts and Technology HND in Software Engineering

Knowsley Tertiary College

OND in Computer Studies

Higherside Comprehensive School

7 O' levels including Maths, English and Computer Studies

Swift

RPG

COBOL

BASIC

C (basic understanding)

GitHub Repository

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

2014 - Round Table President (Bourne)

2014 - Burghley Rat Race 20 Mile Assault course

2008 - Round Table Chairman (Bourne)

2006 - London Marathon

2005 - BUPA North Half Marathon